Are you free?
你是自由的吗
Rouge Redstar.
露琼・雷德斯塔
Father.
爸爸…
(Metallic Rouge)
《金属口红》
You should have killed by Giallon.
你应该早己死在迦隆手上才对
Is he a Nean?
难不成…他是涅安吗
Are you a fake Junghardt?
容格的冒牌货吗
No, he's real.
不对 他是真的
He is the real father.
是真正的爸爸
Right, Rouge.
没错 露琼
No.
不对
This guy is a fake.
这家伙是冒牌货
That's rude, my child.
你这话说得还真是难听啊 我的孩子
I have a Nean body just like you.
亏我还跟你一样 拥有一副涅安的身体呢
However,
然而
a Nean is also a product that imitates humans.
涅安也是模仿人类的产物
In that sense,
在这层意义上
maybe I am a fake as you said.
或许确实如你所说 我是个冒牌货也说不定
But,
但是…
I got the real deal here.
这里是货真价实的
Memories library.
记忆图书馆…
I think it's a system that can store human memories on external devices?
我记得那是能以外部设备 储存人类记忆的系统对吧
Did he upload his personality into a cloned Nean before being killed by Giallon?
他是在被迦隆杀死前 将自己的人格载入复制的涅安里吗
I got killed by Giallon?
迦隆? 杀了我?
Silvia never actually asked Giallon to monitor me.
希尔维雅根本 没有命令迦隆来监视我
In other words,
也就是说
Giallon didn't understand Silvia at all.
迦隆根本就不了解 希尔维雅的言外之意
Nor did he come to monitor me.
也没有来对我进行监视
So he didn't come to kill me.
所以他也没来杀死我
Stop talking nonsense.
你少胡说
This is not nonsense.
这不是胡说
Then, who
那么 我究竟…
did kill me?
是被谁所杀呢
The only person who can kill me
能杀死我本尊的人…
is only me.
只有我自己
Impossible.
不可能
I have…
我明明就…
Then think about it.
那你试着回想一下吧
When and where did you ask him to monitor me?
你在何时何地 下令让他来监视我的呢
That's easy.
这还不简单…
I was
我是在…
-in Rio de Janeiro. -In the space station in Rio de Janeiro.
-在里约热内卢… -在里约热内卢的太空站里
It was a rainy day, right?
那天是个下雨天对吧
That was the day I set.
那是我设定的日子
You liar!
你骗人…
Once upon a time,
过去在某个地方
there was a puppetmaster who pursued eternity.
有个追求永恒的操偶师
This puppetmaster used magic
这个操偶师使用魔法
to transfer his own memories and consciousness to a puppet.
将自己的记忆与意识 转移至人偶身上
Then, he erased his body that has long since aged
再将自己那早己老去的容器抹杀
to become a new seed,
成为新的种子
and transformed into a new being and travelled to higher places.
化身为新的存在 前往更高的所在
It was the desire of his aged body.
这是他那陈旧身躯的内心愿望
Cyan.
希安
The puppetmaster built nine puppets
操偶师在过去年长之时
before he transferred.
制造了九具人偶
Although they are puppets,
它们虽是人偶
they all have self-awareness and live freely.
却都有自我意识 自由地活着
No.
不对
It's what they believe.
是操偶师让它们这么想的
From their birth, they've been manipulated by the puppetmaster with invisible threads.
它们打从诞生以来 就被操偶师用看不见的丝线所操控
And everything they see, hear, and think is under the control of the puppetmaster.
它们的所见所闻所想 全都在操偶师的掌控之中
And,
而且…
their minds are also under his control.
它们的心 也在他的控制之下
You liar!
你骗人
In order to protect humans,
它们为了守护人类
they came forward and fought the demons called Usurpers.
不惜挺身而出 与天外飞来 名为"篡夺者"的恶魔展开战争
But all they had learned on the brutal battlefield
然而 它们在残酷战场上所了解到的
was the ugliness and selfishness of humans,
就只有人类的丑陋与自私
so they become enlightened,
于是它们醒悟了
realizing that they are merely puppets after all,
了解到自己终究只是人偶
and simply tools to be discarded after use.
只是个用过即丢的道具
Therefore, after the battle with the demons ends,
所以在结束与恶魔的战斗后
they parted ways with humans
它们与人类分道扬镳
and vanished without a trace.
就此消失
They thought they rebelled against humans of their own will,
它们以为自己 是靠着自身的意志来反抗人类
but that's not true.
但事实并非如此
Even in term of that,
就连这一点
they have only been manipulated by their master, the puppetmaster.
也都只是被它们的主人 也就是操偶师所操弄
He is the world's playwright and creator.
他是这个世界的剧作家 亦是创作者
All the plots are melodies created by him.
所有情节都是他所编织的旋律
Why are you doing this to us?
为什么要对我们做这种事
The Puppetmaster wants to do a test
操偶师想做个测试
to see if these puppets can be humans,
测试这些人偶是否能成为人类
and if they can surpass humans.
测试它们 是否能超越人类
Shut up!
闭嘴
Aes.
艾斯
Noir.
诺瓦尔
I…
这…这种事
will never accept it.
我绝不认同…
I am
我是…
determined by my own will
凭着…自己的意志…
-to liberate Neans. -To liberate Neans.
下定决心要解放涅安…
Even that idea is part of the setting.
就连这份决心 也不过是设定之一
So is the Noir's love for Eva.
诺瓦尔对艾娃的爱也是
Exactly.
没错
I did it on my own.
那也是出自于我的手笔
What?
咦
Eva was fascinated by Noir she created,
艾娃被自己所制造的诺瓦尔所吸引
that is a feeling for the opposite sex.
从一个异性的角度
You scumbag.
你这个人渣
Do you play with them like they're toys?
你把他们两个当成玩具 玩弄在掌心之中吗
I am fulfilling Eva's wish.
我是在实现艾娃的心愿
And it results in
而这个结果…
the birth of Gene.
就是吉恩的诞生
Keep going.
继续作业
You can definitely do it.
你一定办得到的
It doesn't matter if my thoughts
我内心的思念是真是假
are true.
一点也不重要
Eva's love for you
艾娃她对你的爱
is absolutely true.
是千真万确的
Move, Gene.
动作快 吉恩
Setting?
设定?
What an unexpected turn of events.
意外的发展 急转直下是吧
Interesting.
有意思
Fantastic!
太棒了
This is not some setting.
才不是什么设定…
No.
不…
This is the setting.
这是设定…
You!
你这家伙
-What? -Cyan.
什…希安
Such minor injuries…
这种小伤
Cyan.
希安
Why?
为什么…
It seems the second me
看来第二个我
is proceeding with the plan smoothly.
将计划进行得很顺利
What?
咦
That guy also has consciousness
那家伙的体内 也有爸爸的…
of Father, Dr. Junghardt.
容格博士的意识…
Rouge.
露琼…
Please
求求你…
protect the future of Neans.
守护涅安的未来…
Protect our world.
守护…我们的世界…
Silvia.
希尔维雅…
All nine files of ids have been acquired.
九颗伊德里的档案全都到手了
Then…
剩下就是…
I'm not giving it to you
我不会把它交给你的
absolutely.
绝对不会…
(Episode 13: Code Eve)
(13 CODE EVE)
Rouge.
露琼
Didn't you say that they are equally powerful?
双方性能不是不分轩轾吗
But now Rouge uses my id.
现在在露琼体内的 是我的伊德
And I am not a combat-type Nean.
而我并非是战斗型涅安…
Eva Kristella.
艾娃・克利丝缇勒
Indeed she's the one I admire.
不愧是我看上的人
I can't believe she created something like you.
居然能创造出像你这样的作品
And,
而且
you are closer to humans than the Nine who were created before you.
跟在你之前制造出来的九人相比 你更为接近人类
You started out in ignorance,
你从懵懂无知开始
and little by little, as humans do, you formed self-awareness,
如同人类一般 一点一滴地形成自我意识
and you've grown quickly.
而且还是在短时间里
Eva really did leave something interesting for me.
艾娃还真的是 留下了个有趣的东西给我呢
Rouge, Code Eve,
露琼 CODE EVE
and Gene.
以及…吉恩
Unfortunately,
但是很可惜
I am just an ordinary human.
我只是个平凡人类
At that time,
那个时候
from the data left behind by my mother,
你从母亲遗留下来的资料里
you learned the whereabouts of Code Eve.
知道了CODE EVE的下落
Thus, you set this up
于是你设计了这场戏
to leave me the clues of the Immortal Nine,
将九人的线索留给我
to have Rouge retrieve id and see how she grows.
为的就是让露琼去追回伊德 并借此观察她会有何成长
Everything is your experiment,
一切都是你的实验
the drama created by you.
是场自导自演的大戏
There were some unexpected twists,
也出现了些意料之外的桥段
but it's time for everything to end.
但一切也该闭幕了
Rouge.
露琼
When the old curtain falls,
当老旧帷幕落下之时
a new stage will also be revealed.
新的舞台也将随之开幕
All Neans will be liberated,
所有的涅安都将获得解放
achieving a higher evolution.
进而得到更高的进化
Out of this chaos, a race beyond humans will be born.
在这片混沌之中 将会诞生超越人类的种族吧
And in this new world,
而在这个新世界里
I'll be the one who plays the symphony.
将由我来奏出乐章
Alice.
艾莉斯
Save it.
不用你说
Is there nothing we can do?
就没有什么办法了吗
Tell Rouge to use that phase thing again.
叫露琼再用一次那招相位什么的…
No way.
没办法
Now Rouge uses my id.
现在露琼身体里的 是我的伊德
My
我的…
id.
伊德…
Rouge, reverse the output phase.
露琼 将输出的相位反转
You've done it once before.
你之前也做过一次
But instead of releasing the phase, this time you gather it towards id.
但是这次不是将相位释放 而是往伊德聚集
Then your id will…
这样的话你的伊德会…
Trust me.
相信我
Because we
因为我和你…
will never part.
是永不分离的
I see.
我知道了
I trust you.
我相信你
Concentrate.
集中…
What?
嗯?
Oh?
哦…
Deform.
变形
What's wrong? What is this feeling?
怎么了 这是什么感觉…
In my body,
在我的体内…
this is
这是…
Naomi's id.
直美的伊德它…
Has
难不成…
she arrived?
是抵达了吗
Impossible.
不可能
I…
我…
What…
究竟…
Go, Rouge.
上吧 露琼
Naomi.
直美?
I'm here.
我在这里啦
I've told you
我不是说过了吗
we will never part.
永不分离
Terrible.
糟透了…
What?
什么
So, have I become stronger?
所以呢 我变强了吗
Who knows.
天晓得
Hmm.
嗯
We'll know once we try.
试了就知道
What?
什…
How is it?
怎么样
Cool.
帅啊
Take him down, Rouge.
干掉他 露琼
Why?
为什么
In my calculations, Gladiator should not have this function.
在计算上 斗士化应该没有这种功能才对
That's true if it's just me.
只有我一个人的话 确实如此
I see.
原来如此
If you can reach this level…
如果你能抵达这个领域的话…
Now it's Naomi and me.
现在是我和直美两个人
I became one with Cyan too.
我也与希安合而为一了
Then…
那么…
Have I been rejected?
我被拒绝了吗
Cyan.
希安
Why don't you understand my love?
为何不理解我的爱
Became one with me.
跟我合而为一吧
Cyan.
希安
Are you still there?
你还在那里吗
Do you want me to take him down?
你是要我打倒他吗
But if that's the case, you will…
但这样的话 希安你就…
Cyan.
希安
Even you did that?
连你也是吗…
Why do all of you
为何你们这些人…
reject me?
都要拒绝我
My…
我的…
My wish will not disappear.
我的心愿不会消失…
Even if I lose this body…
即便失去了这副躯体…
Gene,
吉恩
I still have you.
还有你在
My dear Gene.
我无比心爱的吉恩啊
You are me.
你就是我
I am you.
我就是你…
I am me.
我就是我
I will not never be you.
不会成为你
Why do you all leave me alone?
为何你们都要放我孤身一人…
Because being alone suits you better.
孤身一人更适合你
Actually
其实…
you are aware of this, right?
您自己也察觉到这一点了吧
You will be like this as well.
你也会变成这样的…
I don't want
我不要…
to be alone.
孤身一人…
Cyan.
希安
Sister.
姐姐…
Your new form
你的新形态…
looks cool.
很帅哦…
I won.
我打赢了
Because I have you fight with me.
因为有希安和我一同奋战…
Am I your younger sister now?
我有成为了吗…
Your real younger sister.
成为姐姐真正的妹妹…
You are my younger sister.
你是妹妹
Cyan, you are my real younger sister.
希安是我的…我真正的妹妹
Sister.
姐姐…
Let's have pancakes together.
我们…再一起…吃松饼…
I'm sorry.
对不起
It's useless to stop her, right?
阻止她也是没用的…是吧
This is what Eva wanted.
这一定也是艾娃所期望的
Do you really let me do whatever I want?
你真的觉得可以随我高兴吗
Haven't you already decided?
你不是已经决定了吗
What is the future of this rotten world?
这个烂透的世界未来将会如何
Forget it. Let's just do whatever we want.
算了 就走一步算一步吧
This is our style.
这才是我们的行事风格
Exactly.
没错
We are free.
我们是自由的
What?
怎么了
Thank you for your help.
感谢您的大力协助
Rouge Redstar.
露琼・雷德斯塔
This system has a program that inserts a virus
这个系统里设有 在CODE EVE启动的同时
into all Neans when Code Eve is activated.
对所有涅安植入病毒的程序
In this way, all Neans
这样一来所有的涅安
will be the ones who fight alongside us, Junoid.
将会成为与我们由诺伊德 一同战斗的存在
Usurpers.
篡夺者…
Looking forward to meeting you all on the battlefield one day.
期待哪天在战场上与各位再会
On the battlefield where we crush humans.
在我们击溃人类的战场上
We are looking forward to that day.
我们会诚心期待那天的到来
What's wrong?
怎么了
Hey.
喂
I…
我…
Sorry, it's me…
抱歉 是我…
What's wrong?
咦 怎么了
This is…
这是…
All is at peace.
天下太平
Honestly,
老实说啊
Gene had figured out what the Usurpers are up to,
吉恩早就发现了篡夺者在盘算什么
so he put an anti-virus program in the system.
所以在系统里放了反毒程序
Great, my son.
真不愧是我儿子
Please stop.
请不要这样
Hey.
喂…
What am I really…
我究竟是…
How dare you to scare me, Scar Head!
居然敢吓我 你这个疤脸
No one knows
今后的时代…
how the next era will evolve.
没人知道将会如何演变
Come on.
来
Will the world really change?
世界真的会有变化吗
It will change gradually.
会慢慢改变的
From now on, let us make the change.
今后…由我们来改变
That girl's leading the charge.
是那家伙带头指挥呢
Oh my.
真是的…
She's that polite.
这么讲礼数
Hey.
嘿咻
Forget it. Let's just do whatever we want.
算了 走一步算一步吧
Yes.
是啊
Let's just do whatever we want.
走一步算一步
Let's go.
我们上
No problem, partner.
没问题 搭档